remarkable.com 2017-02-25

# Privacy Policy: Safari

This version (Version 3.2) of Safari's Privacy Policy is effective as of November 10, 2016.

This Policy (the "Policy") discloses the privacy practices of Safari Books Online, LLC ("Safari," "we," "us," "our") with respect to the websites that Safari owns and operates and that link to or display this Policy. Those websites include [www.pubfactory.com](http://www.pubfactory.com/) and [www.safaribooksonline.com](https://www.safaribooksonline.com/). This Policy governs how Safari collects, stores, processes, transfers, uses, and protects personally identifiable information that it collects from and about you with respect to those sites. Other Safari websites display or link to the privacy policy that applies to them.

Please note that any use you make of any Safari service offering (including uses in preview mode, on a free trial basis, or pursuant to your purchase of a membership or other service offering) is also subject to our [Membership Agreement](https://www.safaribooksonline.com/membership-agreement/) and our [TOS](https://www.safaribooksonline.com/terms/). By accessing or using any website that links to or displays this Policy, you agree to the terms of the Policy, and you also certify that you are at least 13 years old, and that if you are between 13 and 18 years old, you have obtained the consent of your parent or legal guardian to use the relevant site. Do not use our websites if you do not agree to this Policy, and the TOS and Membership Agreement.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

## QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS: CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this Policy or questions or complaints about our privacy practices, please contact us by email at [customer-service@safaribooksonline.com](mailto:customer-service@safaribooksonline.com) or by mail at:

Safari Books Online, LLC  
Attn: Customer Service  
1003 Gravenstein Hwy North  
Sebastopol, CA 95472 

### 1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Personally Identifiable Information ("PII") means information that can be directly associated with you (such as your name, email address, telephone number or billing information), or information about activities directly linked to you (such as subscriptions that you have licensed or purchased). We collect PII in the following ways:

#### 1.1 INFORMATION THAT YOU PROVIDE TO US DIRECTLY:

When you contact or communicate with Safari, we may gather information such as your name, physical address, email address and phone number.

When you participate in a promotional offer (such as a trial subscription) and/or purchase products or services, we may gather information regarding the offer that you participate in, and any products or services that you purchase, as well as financial information such as your credit card number. When you register for an online account, subscribe to a newsletter, participate in communities or an event, program, class or promotion, or click on a URL, we may gather user preferences, product interests, industry focus, community choices and other customer profile information.

#### 1.2 INFORMATION WE COLLECT THROUGH TECHNOLOGY RELATED TO OUR PRODUCTS AND SERVICES:

Certain products and services that you acquire from us may connect and transmit telemetry and system/product data to us or our authorized agents. This data may include, but is not limited to, system model, operating system, host ID and IP address.

We use this information to manage and administer our products and services, and as the basis for advising you of the availability of updates and new versions, testing and monitoring services that we provide, enhancing our products and services, and improving and targeting our communications with you.

#### 1.3 INFORMATION WE COLLECT THROUGH ONLINE TECHNOLOGY:

We use cookies for authentication, to remember users’ settings, and to improve user experience and the overall quality of our service. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by us and our affiliates, and other companies with whom we do business, such as technology service providers, analytics providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports from these companies based on the use of these technologies by these companies, and the reports may be based on the analysis of individual and/or aggregated usage.

**Analytics / Log Files** \- As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We may from time-to-time engage a third-party advertising network to either display advertising on our Website or to manage our advertising on other sites. That third-party company may use technologies such as cookies to collect non-personally-identifiable information about your activities on our websites and other sites in order to provide you with targeted advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union, click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads; you will continue to receive generic ads.

We use Local Storage (LS) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS.

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook and Twitter sign on buttons. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets may be hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these third-party features are governed by the privacy policy of the companies providing the features.

#### 1.4 INFORMATION FROM OTHER SOURCES:

From time-to-time we may receive information from other sources, such as commercial contact lists or companies that we acquire, and we may combine that information with information previously collected. If you give us PII on behalf of someone else (or someone else gives us PII on your behalf), we require that the person providing the PII to us must have consent to do so from the person whose information is provided. To request the removal of your PII, whether it was provided by you, by a friend, or by a third party marketing company, please see the "Access and Accuracy" section below.

Some Safari events, websites or services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with a third party. When you provide PII in relation to them, both Safari and the third party(ies) may receive the information collected and use the information according to each company's privacy policy and agreement with you. We recommend reading the privacy statement of our co-branding partners as well, if you are accessing our services through a co-branded offering.

### 2\. HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use PII to conduct business, provide information and support for products and services, improve our understanding of your needs and interests, develop and improve our services and products, and personalize communications. Examples include:

  * Advising you of relevant promotions, products, services, and news about Safari and affiliated third parties
  * Processing and fulfilling orders
  * Creating and monitoring accounts
  * Market research projects
  * Analyzing how our products and services are used
  * Personalizing content
  * Advertising including but not limited to remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. We may base the content and placement of ads for Safari service offerings on third party sites across the internet, based on information provided to us by third party services such as Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting.
  * Monitoring our services in order to prevent and identify unauthorized content use and violations of our membership agreements
  * Planning and forecasting
  * Maintaining legal compliance, and preventing fraud and prohibited or illegal activities.
  * We use information collected directly from you in order to monitor website traffic, personalize our website, and to improve our website. 

### 3\. HOW WE SHARE AND DISCLOSE PII

We will not sell your information to third party companies for their promotional use. We may share or disclose your PII with:

  * Companies that are related to Safari, in order to support business and marketing processes
  * Our service providers and suppliers, who are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. For example, we use a third party payment processor in order to bill you for the goods and services you have purchased, an email service provider to send communications to you on our behalf, and a third party "Live Chat" service that helps provide customer service.
  * Our websites include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Safari. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.
  * As necessary, if we suspect a violation of our policies or to protect the rights or safety of any person or entity
  * Government agencies, law enforcement agencies and others, based on a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to respond to judicial process, valid government inquiry, or is otherwise required by law.
  * The buyer, if Safari or any of its assets are sold. In the event of a sale of Safari or its assets, you will be notified via a prominent notice on our website of any related change in uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding those changes.
  * Other third parties for purposes you have allowed by giving us your prior consent.
  * Others including without limitation other participants, to the extent of any PII that is posted by you or an authorized third party to our wikis, forums, blogs, message boards, chat rooms and other social network environments.

Our website offers a publicly accessible blog. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact our customer service team. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [customer-service@safaribooksonline.com](mailto:customer-service@safaribooksonline.com).

### 4\. NOTICE AND CHOICE

We provide notice about our use of PII in this Policy, in our web pages, and in other locations where we collect information. You can choose whether or not to provide your PII to us. If you choose not to provide PII, you may be not be able to take advantage of certain offers, options, events, website features, and services that depend on accurate PII.

To opt-out from or change your marketing communications, preferences, sign in to your account and go to the Email Preferences section of the My Account page or Settings page. You may also opt-out of receiving newsletters or other communications by following the opt-out instructions included in each newsletter or communication. Please note that your marketing communication preferences do not affect transactional, relationship and legally required communications.

You can opt out of our Google Analytics data collection by using the tools available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). You can opt-out of certain aspects of Google Analytics by using Google’s Ads Settings tool.

### 5\. ONWARD TRANSFER

We will only transfer personal information to third parties if those third parties provide an adequate level of data protection to help ensure the security of personal data.

### 6\. SECURITY

Safari uses administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect the security, confidentiality and integrity of PII against loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. In addition, we use standard security protocols and mechanisms (such as secure socket layer [SSL] encryption) to transmit sensitive data such as credit card details. You can assist us in protecting your PII by keeping your password and login information secret, and making sure that you terminate user sessions, close the browser, and log out when you access our services from shared computers. Please note that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at: [customer-service@safaribooksonline.com](mailto:customer-service@safaribooksonline.com).

### 7\. ACCESS AND ACCURACY; UPDATING, CORRECTING OR DELETING INFORMATION; HOW LONG PII IS RETAINED

It is important to us to maintain the accuracy of your contact information. We provide individuals with reasonable access to their PII in order to have it corrected, amended or deleted where it is inaccurate or inappropriate for the specified purposes of processing.

If you need to update, correct, or request the deletion or deactivation of your information please do so by email at: [customer-service@safaribooksonline.com](mailto:customer-service@safaribooksonline.com). You also may update your information by writing to:

Safari Books Online, LLC  
Attn: Customer Service  
1003 Gravenstein Hwy North  
Sebastopol, CA 95472 

We will respond to all requests for access within 30 days. We will make reasonable efforts to incorporate the changes as soon as possible. Before we make changes, we may ask you to verify your identity and/or provide other details. We may keep a copy of the prior information for our records.

We will retain your PII for as long as your account is active, and as necessary to provide you services, to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements.

### 8\. CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

Safari's websites and marketing are not directed to children under 13 years of age.

### 9\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS OF PII

Safari transacts business throughout the world and has operations, processes and systems that cross borders. If you choose to provide us with information, including PII, you understand that we may transfer it within Safari in the United States or to affiliates, joint venture partners, and third party service providers around the world, including to countries which may not require an adequate level of protection for your PII compared with that provided in your country. However Safari works closely with its customers, affiliates, and third party service providers to ensure that all requirements under local law are adhered to facilitate or otherwise legitimize any such transfers.

### 10\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Please note that this Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Policy without your explicit consent. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We will also keep prior versions of this Policy in an archive for your review.

### 11\. FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS: YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS AND DO NOT TRACK DISCLOSURE

Safari’s policy is to share your personal information only if you have given us your consent, for instance, by your agreeing to this Policy through your use of our sites. After obtaining such consent, Safari may in accordance with this policy from time to time provide its business partners with contact details for direct marketing purposes of relevant services, products, and programs. If you no longer wish your information to be shared, please let us know, or if you have further inquiries regarding our information sharing practices, please let us know. You can email us at [customer-service@safaribooksonline.com](mailto:customer-service@safaribooksonline.com).

California law requires us to let you know how we respond to web browser Do Not Track (DNT) signals. Because there currently isn't an industry or legal standard for recognizing or honoring DNT signals, we don't respond to them at this time. We await the result of work by the privacy community and industry.

### 12\. PREVIOUS VERSIONS

For the previous version [Version 3.1] please click here. This is version 3.2.
